<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Certification on Chiggins&#39; Thoughts</title>
    <link>http://chigstuff.com/categories/certification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Certification on Chiggins&#39; Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:05:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://chigstuff.com/categories/certification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hey, I did the OSCP!</title>
      <link>http://chigstuff.com/blog/2015/04/28/hey-i-did-the-oscp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:05:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chigstuff.com/blog/2015/04/28/hey-i-did-the-oscp/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So over the past handful of months I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking some time and worked on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.offensive-security.com/information-security-training/penetration-testing-with-kali-linux/&#34;&gt;Penetration Testing with Kali Linux&lt;/a&gt; training, which in turn I took the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.offensive-security.com/information-security-certifications/oscp-offensive-security-certified-professional/&#34;&gt;Offensive Security Certified Professional&lt;/a&gt; exam! It took a while for me to be able to work through all the training, but as of April 27th, 2015, I am OSCP certified!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-training:ea7ea5bdd4720864502ddb7dea3c961e&#34;&gt;The Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of last summer I was able to start the training course, and had two months of lab time. I really recommend spending the first handful of days to go over the reading and video materials. They will really help you out when you&amp;rsquo;re going through the lab and you&amp;rsquo;ll know where to reference stuff at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start your first couple nmap scans on the lab network, don&amp;rsquo;t get overwhelmed at the number of machines you find and the total amount of information. Take as many notes as you can, I ended up using Evernote for my notes since that will sync across all the devices I used. Keeping great notes will only help you in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the lab machines, there really is a wide range of machines across various difficulty levels. There are a handful of boxes that will seem pretty easy to exploit, but then there are a good number that will leave you banging your head against a wall. If you get too stuck, the Offensive Security forums and the #offsec IRC channel are both great resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to get a lot of the exercises and training done in my first two months, but with the combination of work, the training, and more school work than I anticipated, I ran out of time before I finished what I wanted to and felt comfortable with. I ended up taking a bit of time off from the training and cleaned up a lot of my notes so I would be more prepared for my last attempt at the lab. This March I purchased 15 more days which would overlap with my spring break and spent every day working on the labs, attempting to get as many machines as I could. I learned a lot over the training and finally scheduled a time for my exam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-exam:ea7ea5bdd4720864502ddb7dea3c961e&#34;&gt;The Exam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My exam was scheduled to start at noon on Friday, April 24th. I got everything as prepared as I could, had my training lab report and exercise report all straightened out, and was damn near ready to go. Once I got my exam instructions I was going to town. There were times I knew I was doing well, there were times I was super frustrated, and some times where I needed to take a step back and do something to take my mind off the challenges like make dinner or do some dishes. I ended up getting enough points to pass after about twelve hours into the exam, so I figured that was a good point to get some sleep. I woke up early the next day but didn&amp;rsquo;t score any more points. I spent a few hours putting together my exam report and I was done way earlier than I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be. I submitted all of my documentation and awaited a pass/fail email!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I woke up to get ready for work Monday morning, first thing I saw on my phone (minus an annoying alarm clock) was an email from Offensive Security saying that I passed and had obtained my OSCP! I was beyond ecstatic to say the least!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-conclusion:ea7ea5bdd4720864502ddb7dea3c961e&#34;&gt;The Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I took longer than I would&amp;rsquo;ve liked on the training and lab environment, I felt like it was well worth it. I learned a whole lot, and one of my favorite things about the lab environment is how much it felt like a real corporation. I honestly feel like I became one with the &lt;strong&gt;THINC.local&lt;/strong&gt; domain and learned a bunch from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I want to spend some time looking into more exploit development and malware analysis while also focusing on finishing up my masters degree. Hell, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll even be able to go after the OSCE soon! Thanks to Offensive Security for the training and certification and the staff for all the help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>